<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Dennys Diary</title>
    <link>https://dennys.github.io/en/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Dennys Diary</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>Copyright © 2008–2018, Steve Francia and the Hugo Authors; all rights reserved.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 04 Dec 2022 10:00:00 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://dennys.github.io/en/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Search Google Photos by Device</title>
      <link>https://dennys.github.io/en/doc/software/google-photos-search-by-device/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Dec 2022 10:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dennys.github.io/en/doc/software/google-photos-search-by-device/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Requirement I&#39;m trying to search photos in Google Photos by device name, but it&#39;s strange... I have a Google Pixel 5, if I use Google Pixel 5, I can get all photos, but if I only use Google Pixel, it only shows partial photos. I don&#39;t know the actual rules, the following is my test results.
Apple iPhone 6 Apple iPhone 11 Apple iPhone XS Max Apple iPad (6th generation) Google Pixel 5 samsung SM-M135F (Samsumg Galaxy M13) samsung SM-G935F (Samsung S7 edge) Panasonic DMC-G6 Panasonic DMC-G2 SONY DSC-RX100M5A And you can use Apple, Google, Samsung to find their devices, but it will search some othes photos.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>File Search/Replace Tool</title>
      <link>https://dennys.github.io/en/doc/software/file-search-and-replace-tool/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Oct 2022 10:18:32 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dennys.github.io/en/doc/software/file-search-and-replace-tool/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Requirement Try to find software that can search or replace text in files, and it should support these functions:
Free software. Supports UTF-8. It can show partial find content in the search result (or it takes lots of time to see the file content). Double click can open the file with the associated editor. Support replace. As fast as possible (of course) Software comparison Compare 3 software, I prefer to use grepWin.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Change Gmail Notification Action from Archive to Delete</title>
      <link>https://dennys.github.io/en/doc/android/gmail-notify-delete-archive/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Oct 2022 06:18:32 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dennys.github.io/en/doc/android/gmail-notify-delete-archive/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Requirement You can choose Archive or Reply in Gmail&#39;s default notification actions. But you can change it.
Solution Open Gmail App&#39;s General setting, change the *Default email notification action&amp;quot;. The default action is Archive, you can change it to Delete. After the configuration, you can delete mail in Gmail&#39;s notification. What&#39;s next It&#39;s better to enable bothe Archive and Delete in notification.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Android Gmail Notification Actions (Archive, Delete, ...)</title>
      <link>https://dennys.github.io/en/doc/android/android-gmail-notification-actions/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dennys.github.io/en/doc/android/android-gmail-notification-actions/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            需求 In previous artiche, we know we can change archive to delete in the Email(Gmail) notification of Android (Reference: http://dennys.github.io/en/doc/android/gmail-notify-delete-archive/) But we cannot enable BOTH, therefore, I try to find a solution in other Apps.
K-9 Mail, ( K-9 Mail Joins The Thunderbird Family ) FairEmail Gmail Let&#39;s review Gmail&#39;s ability, the default action is Archive. Open Gmail App&#39;s General setting, change the *Default email notification action&amp;quot;. The default action is Archive, you can change it to Delete.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GitLab SonarQube Integration with dotNET</title>
      <link>https://dennys.github.io/en/doc/devops/gitlab-sonarqube-integration-dotnet/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dennys.github.io/en/doc/devops/gitlab-sonarqube-integration-dotnet/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            If you want to use SonarQube to scan your code during GitLab&#39;s CI/CD flow, please check the following procedures.
GitLab + SonarQube + .NET Core or .NET 5/6/7/... (docker) Reference this document to integrate GitLab and SonarQube.
Set the environment variable in GitLab
$SONAR_URL: The URL of SonarQube $SONAR_TOKEN: The token to access SonarQube $CI_PROJECT_DIR: This is a predifined variable in GitLab, you can reference https://docs.gitlab.com/ee/ci/variables/predefined_variables.html $CI_JOB_NAME: This is a predifined variable in GitLab, you can reference https://docs.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Prometheus Pulls/Pushes Metrics from/to Another Prometheus</title>
      <link>https://dennys.github.io/en/doc/grafana/prometheus-pull-push-metrics-prometheus/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dennys.github.io/en/doc/grafana/prometheus-pull-push-metrics-prometheus/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Requirement I have 3 Prometheus servers and want to consolidate all of them into 1 Grafana. And one VM (Server C) is in a restricted zone and this zone only permits a special firewall rule from this zone to other zones.
Prometheus A pulls (receive) metrics from Prometheus B In this scenario, we use the Federation feature to pull metrics from another Prometheus. You don&#39;t need to do any changes in Prometheus B, just add a new job in prometheus.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Change Android Default YouTube App (YouTube Vanced, New Pipe, ...)</title>
      <link>https://dennys.github.io/en/doc/android/android-modify-default-youtube-app/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dennys.github.io/en/doc/android/android-modify-default-youtube-app/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            NoticeThis solution is only for Android 11 or below!!!Requirement Android&#39;s default YouTube App is not very convenient, there are lots of Open Source alternatives (YouTube Vanced (removed), NewPipe, ...), although you can install them, if you don&#39;t change the default YouTube App, it&#39;s still inconvenient.
Solution Android Settings -&amp;gt; Apps -&amp;gt; Default apps -&amp;gt; Opening links
It will list all Apps, choose YouTube, and you will see the following screen.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Use Grafana to Manager SonarQube KPI</title>
      <link>https://dennys.github.io/en/doc/devops/grafana-sonarqube-integration/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dennys.github.io/en/doc/devops/grafana-sonarqube-integration/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Requirement Usually we use SonarQube to check the KPI of projects: You can also check the build history of a project: Use Grafana to Manager SonarQube KPI But there are some SonarQube exporters, they can export SonarQube&#39;s KPI to Grafana/Prometheus.
Solution 1 Exporter: https://github.com/dmeiners88/sonarqube-prometheus-exporter: It&#39;s a SonarQube plugin, but it only supports 5 KPIs, and the last commit date is 2018/11/9. It supports SonarQube 7, not sure if it supports 8 or 9, I don&#39;t plan to try it.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Use Grafana to Manage GitLab CI/CD Pipelines</title>
      <link>https://dennys.github.io/en/doc/devops/grafana-gitlab-integration/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dennys.github.io/en/doc/devops/grafana-gitlab-integration/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Change log 2022/10/13: Add some check points. Requirement When there are lots of projects on GitLab, it&#39;s not easy to know the overall build status of their CI/CD Pipelines.
Use Grafana to Manage GitLab CI/CD Pipelines Solution 1: Use GitLab build-in metrics Exporter: GitLab build-in (reference: https://docs.gitlab.com/ee/administration/monitoring/prometheus/) Grafana dashboard: https://grafana.com/grafana/dashboards/10620 This dashboard needs this plugin: https://grafana.com/grafana/plugins/grafana-polystat-panel/ prometheus.yml 1- job_name: &amp;#39;GitLab&amp;#39; 2 scrape_interval: 5s 3 metrics_path: &amp;#39;/-/metrics&amp;#39; 4 scheme: https 5 static_configs: 6 - targets: [&amp;#39;gitlab.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>K-9 Mail 6.200 Supports OAuth 2.0 (gmail)</title>
      <link>https://dennys.github.io/en/posts/202207/k-9-mail-supports-oauth-2.0-gmail/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dennys.github.io/en/posts/202207/k-9-mail-supports-oauth-2.0-gmail/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            K-9 Mail 6.200 is released on 2022/07/08, it add the support to OAuth 2.0. Before it, if you activated the 2-factor verification on your Google account, when you try to use K-9 mail to connect to Gmail, you need to use App Passwords. It&#39;s not convenient, you can reference https://ekiwi-blog.de/en/16841/ to check the detail with a step-by-step video.
In K-9 Mail 6.200 release, it supports for using OAuth 2.0 with Google, Yahoo, AOL, and personal Microsoft accounts (Office365 accounts are not supported yet).
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Batch Photo Files Rename Tools (by EXIF).</title>
      <link>https://dennys.github.io/en/doc/software/batch-photo-files-rename-tools/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Jul 2022 10:18:32 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dennys.github.io/en/doc/software/batch-photo-files-rename-tools/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Requirement Most cameras&#39; filenames are like &#39;DC*****&#39; or &#39;P*****&#39;, I want to find a tool that has the following features.
Batch change filenames to P[photo capture date]-[camera model].jpg. For example, P20220710-101405-iPhone 13.jpg. Can change the camera model string, for example, I want to change &amp;quot;iPhone 6&amp;quot; to &amp;quot;i6&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;DMC-G6&amp;quot; to &amp;quot;G6&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;DSC-RX100M5A&amp;quot; to &amp;quot;R1005A&amp;quot;, ... Can add a serial number automatically when the new filename is duplicated with others. Software There are lots of rename tools.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Skip Podcast&#39;s Introduction</title>
      <link>https://dennys.github.io/en/doc/software/how-to-skip-podcast-intro/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dennys.github.io/en/doc/software/how-to-skip-podcast-intro/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            I usually use Spotify to listen to podcasts, but because I use Spotify with my children, I want to find another Podcast App for my personal use.
And I find Pocket Casts has an interesting feature, it can skip the first or last *** seconds. It means some podcasts have an introduction at the beginning, if you want to skip it, you can do it in this app. (This feature is provided in the free version.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SQL to get 1st record of a range</title>
      <link>https://dennys.github.io/en/doc/database/get-first-record-of-a-range-sql/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dennys.github.io/en/doc/database/get-first-record-of-a-range-sql/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            If you want to get the 1st record of range records, you can use this SQL command.
1SELECT * FROM 2(SELECT DISTINCT rank() over(PARTITION BY a.username ORDER BY a.update_dt desc) rn, a.* 3 FROM table_name a 4 WHERE a.update_dt &amp;gt; p_cur_timestamp 5 AND a.update_dt &amp;lt;= p_cur_timestamp + C_PERIOD 6 ) 7WHERE rn = 1 
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Use GitLab to do .NET 4.8 CI/CD</title>
      <link>https://dennys.github.io/en/doc/devops/gitlab-dotnet4-ci-cd/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dennys.github.io/en/doc/devops/gitlab-dotnet4-ci-cd/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            RemindThis is for .NET 4.8 or below only!!Precondition You already have a GitLab (GitLab Saas or GitLab self-managed). This document is for .NET 4.X, if you want to build .NET core or .NET 5/6/7/..., you can use docker to run GitLab Runner.
Procedure Step 1 - Prepare .NET build environment First, you need to prepare an environment to build .NET application. The easiest solution is to install Visual Studio.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Use IFTTT to send currency exchange rate mail daily</title>
      <link>https://dennys.github.io/en/doc/ifttt/ifttt-send-currency-exchange-rate-mail/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dennys.github.io/en/doc/ifttt/ifttt-send-currency-exchange-rate-mail/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Requirement I want to have daily mail including currency exchange rate information.
Mail subject: include the exchange rate in the mail subject. Mail content: Has some links to banks&#39; exchange rate pages. Include some exchange rate history charts. Solution Use ifttt.com
Create a new Applet on IFTTT
Add a new &amp;quot;If This&amp;quot;
Choose &amp;quot;finance&amp;quot; service
Choose &amp;quot;Today&#39;s exchange rate report&amp;quot;
Choose the input/output currency and trigger time.
Add a new &amp;quot;Then That&amp;quot;
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Use WISE to send currency exchange rate mail daily</title>
      <link>https://dennys.github.io/en/doc/software/wise-send-currency-exchange-rate-mail/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dennys.github.io/en/doc/software/wise-send-currency-exchange-rate-mail/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Requirement I want to have daily mail including currency exchange rate information.
Solution use https://wise.com (no need to register an account)
Connect to https://wise.com/tools/exchange-rate-alerts/ Input the currency exchange rate you want to know and your email address. Mail result You will receive the mail daily.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GitLab Checkmarx CI/CD Integration</title>
      <link>https://dennys.github.io/en/doc/devops/gitlab-checkmarx-integration/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dennys.github.io/en/doc/devops/gitlab-checkmarx-integration/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Purpose Checkmarx is a good tool to do code analysis, but there are 2 pain points during the flow.
Checkmarx can integrate SCM like GitHub/GitLab/..., but it cannot be triggered by by a code commit, it can only schedule the job to run the scan. (If I don&#39;t commit code, I don&#39;t want to waste resources scanning the code.) Checkmarx has a built-in issue tracking system, but I think most people prefer to use their issue tracking system in their Git or JIRA or .
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GitLab Checkmarx SonarQube Integration</title>
      <link>https://dennys.github.io/en/doc/devops/gitlab-checkmarx-sonarqube-integration/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dennys.github.io/en/doc/devops/gitlab-checkmarx-sonarqube-integration/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Purpose In previous article, we know how to integrate GitLab and Checkmarx. In this article, we want to integrate SonarQube too. When we commit code to GitLab, we want GitLab to trigger these actions automatically:
GitLab sends the code to Checkmarx to scan. GitLab triggers SonarQube to scan. SonarQube integrates Checkmarx&#39;s report. Procedure You can reference the official document: https://checkmarx.atlassian.net/wiki/spaces/SD/pages/169246832/SonarQube+Plugin+v8.5.0+and+up
Download the plugin from here, it only supports SonarQube LTS version (for now, it&#39;s 8.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to analyze size of table, index in Oracle</title>
      <link>https://dennys.github.io/en/doc/database/how-to-analyze-size-of-table-index/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 May 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dennys.github.io/en/doc/database/how-to-analyze-size-of-table-index/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Check table size (remember to check last_analyzed_date) 1SELECT * FROM all_tables WHERE table_name LIKE &amp;#39;AB%&amp;#39; Re-analyze table 1ANALYZE table TABLE_NAME estimate statisitics Check index-related information (it doesn&#39;t contain block information) 1SELECT * FROM all_indexes WHERE table_name LIKE &amp;#39;AB%&amp;#39; Re-analyze index: 1ANALYZE index INDEX_NAME validate structure; Check index size: (it only checks the last analyzed index) 1SELECT * FROM index_stats; Others An index needs to be rebuilt, deleting or updating records will NOT free the index block Need DBA to check the block&#39;s definition.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
