<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Android on Dennys Diary</title>
    <link>https://dennys.github.io/en/tags/android/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Android on Dennys Diary</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>Copyright © 2008–2018, Steve Francia and the Hugo Authors; all rights reserved.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 10 Oct 2022 06:18:32 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://dennys.github.io/en/tags/android/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>How to Change Gmail Notification Action from Archive to Delete</title>
      <link>https://dennys.github.io/en/doc/android/gmail-notify-delete-archive/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Oct 2022 06:18:32 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dennys.github.io/en/doc/android/gmail-notify-delete-archive/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Requirement You can choose Archive or Reply in Gmail&#39;s default notification actions. But you can change it.
Solution Open Gmail App&#39;s General setting, change the *Default email notification action&amp;quot;. The default action is Archive, you can change it to Delete. After the configuration, you can delete mail in Gmail&#39;s notification. What&#39;s next It&#39;s better to enable bothe Archive and Delete in notification.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Android Gmail Notification Actions (Archive, Delete, ...)</title>
      <link>https://dennys.github.io/en/doc/android/android-gmail-notification-actions/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dennys.github.io/en/doc/android/android-gmail-notification-actions/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            需求 In previous artiche, we know we can change archive to delete in the Email(Gmail) notification of Android (Reference: http://dennys.github.io/en/doc/android/gmail-notify-delete-archive/) But we cannot enable BOTH, therefore, I try to find a solution in other Apps.
K-9 Mail, ( K-9 Mail Joins The Thunderbird Family ) FairEmail Gmail Let&#39;s review Gmail&#39;s ability, the default action is Archive. Open Gmail App&#39;s General setting, change the *Default email notification action&amp;quot;. The default action is Archive, you can change it to Delete.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Change Android Default YouTube App (YouTube Vanced, New Pipe, ...)</title>
      <link>https://dennys.github.io/en/doc/android/android-modify-default-youtube-app/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dennys.github.io/en/doc/android/android-modify-default-youtube-app/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Notice This solution is only for Android 11 or below!!! Please use Better Open With in Android 12 or above. Requirement Android&#39;s default YouTube App is not very convenient, there are lots of Open Source alternatives (YouTube Vanced (removed), NewPipe, ...), although you can install them, if you don&#39;t change the default YouTube App, it&#39;s still inconvenient.
Solution Android Settings -&amp;gt; Apps -&amp;gt; Default apps -&amp;gt; Opening links
It will list all Apps, choose YouTube, and you will see the following screen.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
